Shirley Xiaolin Xu

Senior Software Engineer | www.xiaolin.ninja | US Citizen

Well-rounded professional, experienced in diverse industries and excels in distributed teams.

Contact



xiaolin-ninja



shxxu



n/a



shirleyxiaolinxu@gmail.com

Summary

I design, develop, & maintain RESTful & GraphQL APIs and optimize the scalability of a Cloud PaaS by day; and explore security vulnerabilities in complex systems by night. I bring to the table the unique combination of technical expertise and business experience.

My multicultural & interdisciplinary background enables me to communicate effectively with diverse groups, process information from different perspectives, and adapt quickly to change.

Education

Master of Science, Cybersecurity

New York University
Expected 2021 | GPA: 4.0

Master of International Affairs.

International Business Management Environmental Policy

University of California, San Diego June 2016

Skills

Languages:

Ruby, Python, Go, Javascript, SQL, C++, Spanish, Chinese, English

Security:

OWASP Top 10, cryptography, network mapping, packet sniffing & spoofing, DNS attacks, SSL & IPSec, threat modeling

Development:

GraphQL, REST, Open Service Broker, Kubernetes, Ruby on Rails, Database management, Objectoriented programming, Test-driven development, Agile development

Fun:

PADI Rescue Diver, Krav Maga Level 3, BASI Pilates Mat Level 1 Instructor

Experience

Senior Software Engineer *Salesforce*

05/2018 - Current

San Francisco, CA, USA

Heroku is a cloud platform as a service (PaaS) & part of the Salesforce ecosystem.

- Design, build, and maintain web services and internal tooling.
 - Authorization & authentication flow; Basic, token-based, & SSO
 - Real-time event processing & cache management
 - Asynchronous request handling, job queuing & polling
 - Database indexing & query optimization
 - Kubernetes sidecar pattern
 - Test-driven development, code review, peer programming
- Automate detection and remediation of platform abuse
- On-call rotation: incident response and customer support tickets
- Mentor interns and Junior Engineers
- Present internal & external demos; represent the company at conferences

Co-Founder

Silverfly Talent Agency

11/2016 - 08/2017

Distributed, East Asia

Boutique talent agency serving Seoul, Shenzhen, Guangzhou, and Hong Kong.

- Connected 400+ freelance international models and performing artists to opportunities, eliminating overhead costs
- Promoted client-based small business through social media and field sales
- Generated leads, negotiated contracts, & maintained client relationships
- Created & presented business proposals consisting of extensive market research, sizing, and revenue forecasting

Student Organizations Advisor International House at UC San Diego

09/2014 - 06/2016

La Jolla, CA, USA

Supervised collegiate chapters of Model United Nations, Rotary International, International Refugee Connection, and other affiliates of International House.

- Mentored student leadership, managed & evaluated interns
- Boosted organization growth: fundraised \$5000+ per year
- Evaluated program ROI, organized & executed events, analyzed attendee feedback, managed budgets, & pioneered marketing initiatives